[upbeat music]
[choir vocalizing]
- ♪ We're breaking
new ground ♪
- I'm in Cortland, Ohio,
a small city
60 miles south of Cleveland,
home of the 4-Star Diner,
one of the few establishments
in town that locals depend on
for work and eating out,
run by Gus and his wife, Avgi.
- [speaking Greek]
♪ ♪
- My name is Konstantinos.
But I go with the name Gus.
Even though I don't like it.
[chuckles]
[upbeat jazz music]
- Oh, my god.
What is this?
- Don't [bleep]
bust my balls, man, now.
- My name is Avgi.
- It's 43 years being together.
Now I have to put up
with her, you know.
- Would you like more coffee?
So I decided to come here
because I knew if
I start a business here,
I would have been successful.
I never dreamed that I'm going
to be a restaurant owner.
But I seen that diners was
the future of my business.
American food, good prices,
a cheeseburger,
a hamburger, Italian, Greek.
We been here 15 years.
- What two sides with that
would you like?
- I would describe
4-Star as like--
it's like my second home.
[upbeat rock music]
- Most of our regulars
come almost every day,
three, four times a week.
Here we go.
- That looks really good.
- We're like family
with our customers.
- Um, Gus.
- Gus.
- Let me tell you about Gus.
- [bleep].
Look at this.
[tense dramatic music]
- They're getting
a lot of complaints.
- People are complaining,
but they're customers still.
- That's OK. I don't care.
- How could you just not care?
- I don't give a [bleep]
right now.
- Don't give a crap, then.
Customers hear everything.
They've heard it all
for 15 years.
- We've had customers walk out.
People say that
they'll never come back.
And it's the way
the customers have
seen him treat his employees.
- Your food is coming all raw.
[bleep] [bleep].
And the liver was raw.
The steaks were raw.
[bleep] [bleep].
- It looks like a lot of Greek.
And then you can't
hear anything
except [bleep] [bleep].
[laughs]
♪ ♪
- I don't trust my staff.
Go light on the gravy.
It looks [bleep] gross.
- Maybe if we had a
second to [bleep] breathe.
- We're not going to be able to
do this with you in the window.
I definitely think Gus needs
to trust us to do our job.
Why is Gus standing over in
the corner just watching you?
What do you do wrong?
And they--
- Hey, we're doing
an interview.
Thank you.
Sorry, you gotta go this way.
- [sighs]
[energetic jazz music]
- Hey, Kyle, where's Lexi at?
Where's Lexi at?
- She's in the back
right there.
- This is annoying.
This is the most annoying thing
about this job.
- Lexi, they're going crazy.
What is their complaint?
- This is more stress
than any day
I've ever had here in my life.
- My name's Lexi, and I'm
the head cook of 4-Star Diner.
So I originally came here
as a server.
And they were really
short-staffed in the kitchen,
so I, you know,
helped out one day.
- Still got [bleep].
- I hear you, Gus.
And then I've been stuck
back here ever since.
- It's [bleep].
Before Lexi, we had three
to four people back there.
I didn't trust them at all.
You know,
I fired them on the spot.
Good.
[energetic jazz music]
- Most of my
lessons from cooking
come from watching
cooking TV shows,
so sometimes steak temps are
wrong or egg temps are wrong.
- Here's your guys' salads.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- I trained her everything.
She was like a sponge.
- I've never been trained.
- [sighs]
- Are you OK?
- No, I'm not.
- You're not OK?
- Look at all the plates.
They're not eating their food.
And we keep throwing
food, food, food, food.
With our property,
I have some loans,
and I'll probably
be dead by then,
and I haven't paid them off.
I gotta spend $5,000
to mop up [bleep] [bleep].
- My whole income is my tips.
And if I don't have customers
in here, I'm not paying bills.
What would I do
if this place closed?
- [speaking Greek]
- This is everything.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- [bleep].
[tense music]
- This restaurant is festering!
You cannot be that deluded!
Stop, stop, stop!
I promise you
you can't do this!
Smell it!
Shut it down!
[upbeat hip-hop music]
♪ ♪
- I am driving through
Cortland, Ohio.
It's a scenic detour about
an hour outside of Cleveland.
Now here as you can see,
it's like a really nice
sense of calm.
It's slow and very,
very beautiful.
Now I'm stopping
by the 4-Star Diner
for what hopefully will be
a really nice, delicious lunch.
Especially after
our long drive.
That's it over there.
♪ ♪
OK, here we are.
Classic American diner.
4-Star Diner,
celebrating 15 years.
Hello.
- Hello.
- Oh, my Lord,
it's busy in here.
- Hello.
- Oh, my god.
Ramsay's here.
Holy crap.
He's sexier in real life
than he is on TV.
- He's here.
You hear me?
- What?
- He's here.
- Oh, my god.
Now I'm nervous.
Um, a little intimidating
having the best chef
in the world in my restaurant.
Oh, my god. He's so awesome.
I can't take it.
- How are you?
- Good. Avgi.
- Avgi. Ah, Gus's wife?
- Yes.
- Lovely.
- Well, well.
- I'd like to go to a seat.
- Yeah.
Shall I sit over there
in the corner?
- Anywhere you like.
- Thank you very much.
Morning.
How are you?
OK.
This is certainly dated,
let me tell you.
It's just a cluster
of knickknacks
and bits of crap
[bleep] everywhere.
As for the deflated balloons,
what a way to celebrate
15 years.
They look so miserable.
Oh, this looks like
the man himself.
Just walked off the catwalk.
- How are you doing, sir?
- Very well, thank you.
How are you?
- Nice.
- We might as well
sit down together.
Are you overdressed
or is it me?
You make me feel all shabby.
Honestly, you're like
an Athens Bee Gee.
- For 20 years,
I was in fashion business.
- Oh, I didn't know that.
- Yes.
- And you're
celebrating 15 years?
- 15 years.
- That's incredible.
Congrats.
- Thank you.
- Well, I'm going to
have a good look around.
I'm going to taste the food.
What would you recommend?
- I recommend the Greek omelet.
- Good. Well,
we'll catch up later, shall we?
- OK, sure.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
[suspenseful percussive music]
♪ ♪
- Good morning.
- How are you?
- I'm doing great.
How are you?
- I'm very well, indeed,
thank you.
- Nice to meet you.
I'm Karen.
- Karen, good to see you.
- OK.
What are we gonna have today?
- Let's start off with
buffalo chicken strips.
Let's do--I saw a burger.
Route 46, right?
And then let's do the salmon,
please.
Thanks, darling.
Oh, the omelet.
Gus recommended
the Greek omelet.
- The Greek omelet.
OK.
- It's in some authentic
Mediterranean flair.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Wow.
- Lexi.
- OK.
- It's Gordon Ramsay's food,
OK?
- OK.
- Do you hear me?
- Yeah.
- No grease, no stuff,
no nothing.
- Kyle, you're going to need
a medium-rare Route 46
as well as the salmon,
all for Ramsay.
I do feel nervous because
he's one of the best chefs
in the world.
I'm an untrained line cook.
I am doing my best.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- Here's our Greek omelet.
- Oh, the Greek omelet.
OK.
I am excited for this omelet.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- No seasoning.
Rubber.
Wow.
Not a good start.
- What's wrong with it?
- Oh, no, it's just--
it's just sort of overcooked.
- Overcooked.
I will let her know.
♪ ♪
- Lexi?
- Yes.
- Gordon Ramsay said
your omelet's overcooked.
- Thank you.
It sucks to hear that because
I do take a lot of pride
in my work and try to make
people happy with the food.
♪ ♪
Buffalo strip.
- OK, these are
buffalo chicken strips.
- These are the homemade ones,
right?
What does that mean?
- I don't--[laughs]
- Ask Gus, 'cause
it doesn't smell like it.
- Gus, buffalo chicken tenders.
What part of that's
our own recipe?
- Only our sauce.
- It is not. It is
straight out of the container.
Thank you.
- Wow, they are dry.
- He says only our sauce.
♪ ♪
- And they're frozen, right?
- Yes.
- Yeah, yeah, I'll bypass it.
Thank you, thank you.
- Sorry about that.
- Very strange.
[indistinct chatter]
- Lexi, he said it was dry
and ugh.
- Thank you.
♪ ♪
- Gus is hovering around
like some funeral bearer
waiting for a coffin
to come out.
So uninspiring.
- Everything's available
on the menu today.
- Thank you.
- OK? No, you're welcome.
Gus is putting on a act.
He's trying to be quiet,
not say anything.
And that's not him.
He usually flips out 'cause
the food times
are not coming out
or they're too slow back here
in the kitchen.
I hope
Gordon sees right through him
and that
he's putting on a show.
♪ ♪
- I'll take what's next.
- OK.
♪ ♪
- You ready for your salmon?
- Oh, my god.
How's the salmon cooked?
- On the grill.
- Frozen veg or fresh veg?
- Frozen.
Thank you.
- You're welcome. Enjoy.
♪ ♪
- Mm.
That tastes disgusting.
And the veg,
it's almost like they've
been cooked in meat juices.
♪ ♪
- You didn't like it?
I saw you spit it out.
- Yeah.
How are they cooking the veg?
What are they doing?
- I really don't know.
- What a mess.
- Thank you.
The salmon was gross
and the veggies were nuked.
So far, he's liked nothing.
- This is not good.
Your Route 46 is going--
- Medium rare.
Here.
- Man, that's quick.
- Enjoy. I'll be back.
- Does it normally
come out this fast?
- It comes up really fast,
pretty much, when Lexi cooks.
- Wow.
- Which isn't very good.
- Does Gus ever
go behind the lines?
- If he does, he's just
a pain in the butt.
- So what does he do here?
- Usually, nothing.
Gets in our way.
He walks as slow as he can.
Let me get you a steak knife.
- Thank you.
So this is the burger.
This smells a little bit weird.
♪ ♪
[sniffs]
Damn.
You have something that
is not right in there.
And I do not know what that is.
- So?
- Yeah, just--
something smells in there.
Is everything clean and fresh?
Is it--do they cook fresh?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Mm.
ry[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Yeah--ooh.
- Everything OK here?
- Yeah, I've had better days,
but all good.
How are you?
- I don't know.
- You don't know.
- If you don't know how
you are, then I'm [bleep].
- I'm going to sit down.
- What's happened?
Why is it failing?
What is happening?
I'm sorry.
Are you OK?
But what are the problems
in the restaurant?
[somber music]
- Are you OK?
- Yeah. I--
[sniffles]
- I'm here to help, OK?
And I'll talk
to all of you after.
- Thank you, Avgi.
Thank you.
- [sniffles]
- [sighs] Ooh.
♪ ♪
[tense music]
- Thank you very much.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
- Let's get--
let's get the entire team out.
- Everybody out front.
- Let's go.
♪ ♪
Listen, I'll be honest.
The whole experience
was just sad.
Gus, this was your dream?
- Yes, it was, and it still is.
- And it still is?
- Yes.
- Let's talk about the food.
It's called 4-Star Diner.
One star, one star, one star.
♪ ♪
Gus, are you proud
of this place?
- Yes, I am.
- What are you proud of?
'Cause I'm struggling.
- Uh--
- Wow.
Feels like we've given up.
- That's exactly how it feels.
- Gus, talk to me.
I have to repeat myself
over and over.
And don't do this,
don't do this,
don't do this, don't do this.
- So your staff
aren't listening to you?
- Yes.
- So it's a staffing issue?
- The simplest thing,
I have to tell them ten times.
- You don't
appreciate us at all.
- I do appreciate them.
Maybe they're not feeling it.
- We're not feeling it.
- Maybe because I don't go
around every day and saying,
oh, you're doing this.
oh, thank you.
Or--yes.
- You know how much better
we'd do if you did that for us?
- But are you encouraging them?
- No.
- You're not
encouraging the team?
- No.
- So you believe it's good food
and good service?
- Yes.
Strongly.
[dramatic music]
- You can't see any problem
in here?
Definitely.
- [chuckling] Yeah.
- Oh, my goodness me.
Wow.
[tense music]
- Gus, are you proud
of this place?
- Yes, I am.
- What are you proud of?
'Cause I'm struggling.
- Uh--
- You don't appreciate us
at all.
- Wow.
- Chef, how many times
can you repeat yourself?
- So your staff aren't
listening to you?
- Yes.
- But the only person not
doing anything today was you.
All I could see was this man
just standing there like that.
I'm like, is he actually
going to do anything?
- Do I do help you out?
- You saw it.
- No.
- Well, when you're in our way
thinking you're helping out,
you're not really helping,
but you think you are.
It's pretty much bullcrap what
Gus was doing,
blaming us for everything when
he does nothing around here.
He don't take any of the blame
and then we feel all degraded.
- OK, an owner
that's in denial.
Can I have a word
with the front of house?
- Sure.
- Do you want to grab
some fresh air and a coffee
and--oh, my Lord.
Dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
What is really going on?
- We're flying by the seats
of our pants every day.
- Gus does tell us
to say that the food
is fresh and not frozen.
- Yeah.
He told me to tell you the
buffalo sauce was homemade.
- Oh, my goodness me, this guy.
Is he on his best behavior
right now?
- Yes.
- 'Cause I'm in the building?
all: Yes.
- How does he normally perform
when I'm not here, truthfully?
- He will yell.
He'll yell and scream at you.
- And this is
in front of customers?
- Oh, yes. Definitely.
- Wow.
OK, can you just show me how
this place functions tonight
and let me have a good look
at how this system works?
- OK.
- Thank you so much.
- We appreciate it.
- Oh, my gosh.
So glad you're here.
- We can breathe?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Chef.
- Well, let's get
one thing clear.
That is not
a four-star performance.
The food is--
it's not even one star.
And there's something going on
a little bit deeper
and I need to get
to the bottom of this quickly.
[suspenseful music]
[upbeat percussive music]
- Everybody ready
to do their job?
- Yep.
- Going into service tonight,
Gus needs
to get his act together
and show how he really is
and not walk on eggshells
because Ramsay's here.
- Hi. How are you?
- Good. How are you?
- Customers coming in.
About to get to showtime.
- How's everybody doing?
- Good.
- Mile-high turkey dinner.
- Just a waffle?
- Yeah.
- Mashed potatoes,
gravy on everything.
- Meat and cheese only
on that Philly, please.
- Perfect.
- Thank you.
- First order, short stack,
full stack French toast.
- OK. If I wasn't here,
what would you do?
- Please don't stop.
- Don't stop.
- OK.
- I tell you what is good
is our roast pork loin.
We make that homemade in-house.
- Lexi?
- Yeah.
- Make sure he doesn't
give no raw food out today.
- Thank god Gus is here
to tell us how to work.
- Thank god for that.
- It is tough having Gordon
Ramsay in here evaluating,
but I definitely am
looking forward to it.
I think it's going
to be for the better,
so very excited to have him
in here critiquing everything.
- Give me an insight
to how this works.
How do you organize the line?
- Fried and egg grill,
I usually run.
- Right.
- He runs main grill,
which is burgers, chicken.
- Right.
- Grilled cheese, home fries.
- Gotcha.
- Medium-rare
on that steak, Hal.
We're gonna pull it off.
- And how do you
section this off?
What goes where?
- I mean, really, however.
Room.
- No?
So there's no organization?
You just throw it on there?
- Right.
- Wow.
♪ ♪
- Hi, guys.
How are you?
- How are you?
- Good. Two?
- Yes.
- OK.
Medium-rare, mashed potatoes.
- Can I ask if you
have a check down there
for a sirloin steak sandwich?
It's been a while, long while.
- Yeah, right here.
It's the one we're
working on now.
- Shouldn't
be too much longer now.
- OK.
- Is that cold?
- You want me to
take them back, guys?
- No.
- You sure?
- I'm so sorry.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- The steak is--mm.
it's very chewy.
- OK.
- Hey, guys,
we got a send-back.
- Oh.
To be honest, I think
this dinner service is a joke.
I think the pressure
is just on having Gordon here.
Tink everybody's feeling
a little bit nervous
and making
a little bit of mistakes.
- Everything good?
- Let me take it
back for you, hon.
♪ ♪
- What did they say is wrong?
- They just say texture
and everything looks gross.
- Is it frozen?
- No.
- It's not frozen?
Then why are they defrosting on
the top of the oven over there?
- It was frozen.
It is thawed now.
- He's just lying.
I know, but he's just
lying to me.
- No, maybe I don't
understand your question.
- Is this product frozen?
- They come frozen
and we cut 'em up.
- So that means yes.
- Yes.
- Right.
OK.
Thank you.
Frozen.
- I think Gus just has
a problem admitting his wrongs.
I think he's just
so used to lying to everybody.
I mean, to lie
to Gordon Ramsay,
to lie to anybody
about it being fresh,
it's just not right.
- All right.
Lexi, are you ready
for this shrimp?
- Yes. There's three orders.
Just plate them.
- You want me to separate it
and what?
- Yeah.
He's killing me.
- He's in the kitchen now
with an apron on.
Is that normal?
Because I'm here?
- No.
- What is he doing?
He's on the grill now.
- He's gonna be in the way.
- And again, do you think
that's because I'm here?
- Yes.
- Wow.
- Where's my olives at?
- They're in the cooler.
- He doesn't know how
to finish these things?
- He's never been back here.
- He's never been back here?
- Ever.
- I think Gus is acting
a little different today.
I think he's a little nervous
to show everybody
his true colors.
- How's my gyro?
Where's my gyro?
- 4-Star Diner it isn't,
let me tell you.
The big issue
I've got right now is Gus.
He's faking it.
And he's going around putting
band-aids on everybody.
This guy is full of [bleep].
Uh, Gus.
- We're gonna get you
some lunch.
- Two seconds?
[tense music]
♪ ♪
What are you doing?
Are you faking it?
- I'm not faking [bleep].
- I'm going to call you out.
You are.
You never go behind the line.
You're jumping in,
you're grabbing bits of food.
It's just--I've never
seen anything like this.
- 100%, I give you
my word as a man.
- Right.
- This is not a fake. Trust me.
- I'm just asking
because everyone's
saying this is not normal.
And I don't trust you.
I've got to be honest with you.
I don't trust you.
I smell a rat.
- What do I have--
what do I have to do?
- I'm just asking you.
- No, no, no
- Is this real?
- It's not fake at all.
- Show me how
you run your business.
- Right.
That's what I'm doing.
- Ugh.
- So gross.
How many times a week
is this kitchen cleaned?
- Deep clean?
None. No times a week.
- Disgusting.
- I wish the cleanliness
was different.
I've been trying
to do what I can,
but Gus did not train me
at all.
- Gus, when was the last time
this kitchen was deep-cleaned?
- Every single night?
- Yeah.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Right.
Fridge time.
Oh, my goodness me.
Look at the state of that.
Bloody hell.
Raw meat sat with cooked meat.
[coughs] Ground burger.
Oh, my god.
Lexi, stop cooking.
- Done.
[dramatic music]
- Gus, come here.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I need to stop you from eating.
I hate to be the bearer
of bad news,
but I was hoping that you were
going to somewhat have at least
a sort of two-
or three-star dinner tonight.
Did someone have
the burger tonight?
- My table did,
but did not receive it yet.
♪ ♪
- Just smell them.
Just smell them.
♪ ♪
That's not fresh.
- I've been trying
to get a date gun
since I started
in this kitchen.
They're just,
you know, not hearing me.
If the health inspector
comes in here--
If anybody comes in here,
you don't know
if it's old, if it's fresh.
- Forget about that [bleep]
and throw it away.
- What did you just say?
Forget about that [bleep]?
- Throw it away.
- How dare you?
- How dare me?
- Can you smell that?
- Yes.
- I am very shocked that Gus
would just not care enough
to make sure that
all of our products are fresh
and not going
to get anyone sick.
- You gentlemen,
OK, how many years
have you been coming here?
Do you ever have a [bleep]
hamburger that smelled?
- OK. Did you think that
I did that purposely?
- This is not yours?
- I'm not responsible to
check every [bleep] letter.
Guys, I'm really sorry, OK?
You don't have to eat it.
You don't have to pay.
- Oh, thank you for that.
You don't have to eat it.
- You don't have to do [bleep].
Please do not come back!
I'm done.
- What?
[dramatic music]
- You don't have to eat it.
You don't have to pay.
- Oh, thank you for that.
You don't have to eat it.
- You don't have to do [bleep].
- I think he's going
to see the real Gus.
I think that Gus is gonna
start ripping us a new one.
- Please do not come back!
I'm done.
- What?
Please go home,
ladies and gentlemen.
♪ ♪
- Thank you guys
for everything, OK?
- So sorry, guys.
Oh, my god.
Our shot at fixing this
restaurant is possibly over.
- What if nobody
ever comes back?
Like, what if
we really do shut down?
I'm not prepared
to be out of work.
- I don't want you
to be prepared.
But right now, I'm banging
my head against the wall
with this guy.
He is not listening.
First, it's your--the staff,
the team not listening.
Now it's the customers.
This guy's deluded.
Where is he?
- I don't know.
Probably ran off.
- Where is he?
I need some time with him
on my own.
- You know how sad it is
to stand out there
and watch him give excuses
like that for us
and put that [bleep] on us?
- Yep.
- Like it's our [bleep] fault?
♪ ♪
- What is wrong with you?
- Like, about what?
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- You're taking advantage
of your customers.
You're taking advantage
of this town.
And you know what?
Your staff, they're petrified.
You show no respect
to the staff.
I need you to wake up.
- [sighs]
- 'Cause ever since
I met you,
all it is is just
excuse after excuse.
You are the problem here.
- [groans] Chef, to be honest,
I don't agree with you.
- Game over, Gus.
- Game over?
The game is never over with me.
Game just started.
- Nah, I'm done
with that [bleep].
And I'm not gonna hang around
with my team to change you.
And the only way
I'd consider staying
is if you get in
every member of your staff
and apologize to them.
♪ ♪
If you're not gonna do that,
then I can't help you.
I'm leaving.
♪ ♪
I am done.
- Where is Gordon?
Do you know where he went?
- Gordon left.
He took off.
- Oh, lordy.
♪ ♪
- I can't stay here
and hang around
if that guy's
not prepared to change.
Trading on 15 years'
reputation,
that's been failing--this guy
needs to show some humility.
He needs to start
apologizing for what he's done
to that loyal team
before it's too late.
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
- Hey, what's going on?
- Nice to meet you.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- What's that?
- When you guys don't have
this diner,
you're gonna be sorry.
- Gordon can't help us if
he is not gonna help himself.
- Do you really think
Gus is gonna own up
to any of what
he showed tonight?
- I'm going to use his words.
This is all [bleep].
- Well, it was nice
knowing you all.
- Hey.
- Stop it.
- Yeah, right.
- He came in here one day,
one [bleep] day,
and he said he ain't coming--
I don't want [bleep]
back in here anyway!
- OK.
- How he [bleep] judge me
in one [bleep] hour?
- Gus is back there screaming.
- We're gonna close.
- [bleep] him!
I don't want--
anyway!
Tell him to get
the [bleep] out of here!
You think I need his [bleep]?
Do you think I need [bleep]?
15 [bleep] years!
- No.
- I don't give a [bleep]!
All right!
Get the [bleep] out of here!
- Oh, my goodness.
[dramatic music]
- Guys, guys get
the [bleep] out of here.
You're all--
- What happened now?
- He left. He ain't
coming back here no more.
- That's because you're not
taking accountability, Gus.
- [bleep] him and
[bleep] all of you.
- No. You [bleep] apologize.
- Get the [bleep] out of here.
- You have to just
take accountability, Gus!
- What you--
- What? In one hour?
- Because we're all
going to walk!
- In one [bleep] hour?
- What are you going to do?
[Gus screaming indistinctly]
You, two hours, like a puppy!
- Right, you have
to apologize to us,
- In one hour! In one hour!
- That's the whole problem.
- He wasn't here to apologize!
- Not him.
You apologize to us.
- You need to try!
- [bleep]
I can't [bleep] right now.
- So what, we're just done?
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Give me a second.
- What are we gonna do?
- No job?
Are you kidding me?
- I don't understand.
- You don't understand?
Ask your [bleep] husband.
- [bleep].
- It's just really upsetting
that Gus would act like this
and not take accountability
that this is his restaurant.
- Look, everybody's
taking their cameras.
They're all leaving.
Go get him.
- He just
pulled the [bleep] out.
He's leaving.
- Are you frigging kidding me?
- I don't believe it.
- What do we do?
- [sobbing]
[engine revving]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- [bleep] [bleep].
- Gus is back there screaming.
- You have to apologize to us.
- In one hour! In one hour!
- That's the whole problem.
- He wasn't here to apologize!
- No job?
Are you kidding me?
Look, everybody's
taking their cameras.
They're all leaving.
- Nobody's going to
come back in here after that.
[engine revving]
- [sobbing]
[suspenseful music]
- I don't know what happened.
He wouldn't apologize to us
and he took off.
And now he's gone.
- [sniffles]
I don't--what do we do now?
What do we do?
- [sighs]
It's been emotional today.
The way that Gus acted--
I mean, I've seen
that side of him.
I didn't think it was going
to get that bad
with Gordon being here.
I mean, I'm glad it was because
he showed his true colors.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- Having heard
the news from my team
that Gus has refused
to apologize to his staff
and abandoned them,
I've decided to come back
and see if I can do anything
to change his mind.
- Sorry, I'm a little bit too
depressed right now to cook.
There would be no love
in that food.
[somber music]
- Oh, my god, he's here.
- Oh, my goodness me.
[sighs]
The producer told me Gus left.
- Yeah.
- He took off.
- He's obviously upset.
I am prepared
to stay for all of you
because I know
you need this to work.
I asked Gus to do one thing,
that he apologize
to the front of house.
- Oh, yeah. That will never
in a million years happen.
- OK, let me call him now.
- Oh, lordy.
- Please, Gus.
Please, Gus.
[tense music]
- Yeah.
- Gus, it's me.
- Yes, Gordon.
- I'm so happy
that he came back.
♪ ♪
- Everybody, everybody.
- I am prepared
to transform this business
if you accept your mistakes
and agree to move forward
with apologizing to the team.
♪ ♪
- And I'm willing to do that.
I can be there in 15 minutes.
- Bye-bye.
He's coming back.
And then we are gonna
get this place
back on the map where
it belongs.
- Yes.
- OK?
- Thank you.
- I appreciate you.
- Come on.
All right.
- I'm feeling pretty relieved,
actually.
I'm feeling pretty hopeful
for our future.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Gordon.
- First of all,
have you calmed down?
- Yes.
- OK. Glasses off, please.
I asked you
one simple thing, Gus.
And that was just to apologize.
I'm here to help,
but I cannot help you
unless you, Gus, the boss,
is prepared to change.
We've got to move forward.
- That's it.
- We go back in there,
apologize,
but talk from the heart.
- Yes.
- Let's go.
[low somber music]
Come on.
Do the honorable thing.
[Gordon sighs]
- The whole staff.
- OK. [sighs]
I'm sorry.
All right?
- You makes everybody here cry.
- I'm sorry.
- This is last time, too,
Gus, last time.
- Honey, I'm sorry
for everything I've done.
[Avgi sighs and chuckles]
Tabitha, I'm sorry.
- I forgive you, Gus.
- OK.
- We got this.
[low somber music]
- Honey, you know
how much I love you.
I'm sorry.
- At least you apologized to
us, and I accept your apology.
- Yeah, we all do.
[soft bright music]
- First thing tomorrow morning,
we start clean, we start fresh,
and we start together.
Then front of house,
we'll start with
a complete new organization
and a setup in this dining
room to be proud of,
to cook for some amazing
locals, but more importantly,
starting to rebuild
this restaurant's reputation.
- Thank you, Ramsay.
We appreciate it.
- Yeah, thank you.
- We really do.
- Yeah.
- We have a lot of work to do.
Ladies, front of house, let's
get everything out of here.
Kitchen, Lex.
- Chef, thank you very much.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
♪ ♪
[Avgi sighs]
- I thought it
was very genuine.
I've never seen Gus cry.
I've never seen him like that.
So for him to do something
like that is very genuine.
- [sobs] Don't you ever leave
us like that again, Gus.
Don't you ever walk out.
- I think he stays now.
I believe that he stays,
because it's
the last chance for Gus.
[dramatic music]
[upbeat jazz music]
- In Cleveland, Ohio,
overnight, I've had my team
come into the 4-Star Diner
to give it a much-needed
refurbishment and deep clean.
♪ ♪
- Oh, my god.
- Wow.
- Oh, it's so beautiful.
- The endless knickknacks
and worn-out furnishing have
been replaced.
- Look at the light fixtures.
- Good morning.
How beautiful is this?
- Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
- Lexi, let's go through
to your new kitchen.
My team have given them
everything they need
to bring the locals back.
New fryers, a new grill,
beautiful new eight-top burner
as well.
- So beautiful.
- Wow.
- New pots and pans,
new knives, new chinaware.
- Whoo!
- Amazing.
My new kitchen.
I am in love.
We've got new HexClad pots
and pans, Microplane graters.
We've got
a new Imperial stove.
I've got a new grill,
new fryers.
I'm very excited for
the dinner service tonight.
I'm so ready to get back
to serving people.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- The 135 items have gone.
- Yes.
Thankfully.
- Tonight,
we are cooking fresh.
It's a diner,
so it's comfort food
that really does
hug your soul.
Firecracker shrimp, a really
nice little sharing dish.
Baked feta. Just a little nod
to the Mediterranean, as well.
Pork chops beautifully done.
And a lovely
buffalo chicken dip.
Sit down. Dig in.
Have a little taste.
[upbeat music]
- That's better than
canned green beans
that we used to have.
- Oh, wow.
The new menu is amazing.
We're in trouble
'cause I just started a diet
and I have to behave now.
- Someone's gonna have
to take this away from me.
- I've also asked Gus
to come at the end of service
because I want
to be able to show him that
you can run the restaurant
better without him around.
- When I found out that
Gus wasn't going to be here,
it actually was nice.
There's no tension.
It feels great.
♪ ♪
- With the reopening
under an hour away,
I brought my team in to help
with the final service,
as well as give Lexi
a one-on-one
to help create a five-star
meal in the 4-Star Diner.
First time we met, you were
cooking an omelet on a griddle.
- Yes, on a flattop.
- So first off,
we don't season the eggs.
If we season the eggs
too early, they'll go gray.
Then from there,
just flip that up.
Flip, flip, flip.
So when the customers from
now on ask for an omelet,
you're going to be cooking
in a pan and doing it properly.
- Beautiful.
- So off you go.
Make me one, please.
- OK.
♪ ♪
- Let's go, girl.
- Oh, my god.
- Well?
- It's delicious.
- I would say I'm a
Gordon-Ramsay-trained chef now.
I'm Chef Lex.
I'm very excited.
Thank you so much.
[suspenseful music]
- How are you feeling?
- I'm feeling good.
- Good.
- Feeling good.
- It's not a race.
- Feeling excited to learn.
- Yeah. Exactly that.
It's not a race.
- No.
- You good?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
I just got that part
of it not being a race.
That's what I gotta remember.
- Yeah, it is definitely
not a race, OK?
You know that, right?
- Well, hello, hello.
Welcome to the new 4-Star.
Tonight, I'm feeling
really excited,
a lot different
from last night.
Most of our regulars
should come back,
Hopefully all of them.
- [speaks Greek]
I'm happy to see you again.
- You are back.
- How lovely.
- Welcome back.
- How is everyone?
Good?
- OK, well, your food
will be over in a minute.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- All right.
Kyle, fire two feta appetizers.
I'm going to fire
two potato skins.
- Louder.
- Two feta appetizers.
And I got
two potato skins going.
- Nice.
- Hi, guys.
How are you?
- Hi. How are you?
- I'm good.
♪ ♪
- OK. Just put these
anywhere to share?
- Yeah.
- OK.
Without Gus here
during the service,
it's just a really
positive atmosphere.
- We're sharing everything.
I like it.
- All right, guys,
here's a buffalo chicken dip.
- How's it tasting so far?
- It's terrific.
- It's good?
- Very good.
- I knew it would be.
[laughing] Good.
- You guys been here before?
- No.
- No? OK, then you don't know
the transformation,
but it's beautiful.
- Everybody enjoying the food?
- Yeah,
they're licking it clean.
[energetic percussive music]
- Lex, good?
- You need two pork chops.
- Pork chops are working.
- Pork chops shouldn't
be too much longer.
- Pork chops still going to
need another minute or two.
It's only at 135.
- Which one?
- This one.
- But what's the temp on those?
- Uh-huh. OK, yeah.
Learning how
to cook pork chops,
you know, that's not frozen,
that's fresh,
I've never cooked fresh
before, so I'm not used to it.
It's also a little bit
nerve-wracking.
- They're what?
- 145.
- They're going to go
in the oven right now.
[dramatic music]
- So where are we at?
- How long on pork chop?
- Uh--
- We need pork chops,
like, right now.
[laughter]
[dramatic music]
- Table five is dragging
right now.
And we're dragging
on two pork chops.
- All right, we need two more
pork chops, like, right now.
- Pork chops shouldn't
be too much longer.
- I've never cooked fresh
before, so I'm not used to it.
It's crazy.
- That pork chop--
is that that one for five?
- Next, we are--
- Then we got one pork chop on.
We've got two pork chops on.
One steak, we've got two on.
So we'll stay in front of that
and let it rest.
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Don't worry.
I'm on it. I'm on it.
Well, let's go.
♪ ♪
- Having Gordon Ramsay
jump in and help,
it's eased my nerves
a little bit.
And now I know
that we can do this.
[upbeat music]
Sandwiches are here.
Pork chops are working.
- Great. OK.
Let's get fries on there.
You can go ahead
and start firing
the veg for the pork chop.
- Two sides of broccolini.
- Love that.
- There you go.
- That pork chop is flying out.
- Ooh.
- Thank you.
- You are so welcome.
- Lex, you good?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
Not so nervous now, right?
- No. Great.
Loving it.
- Good, good, good.
- The buffalo dip.
- OK, here's our feta cheese.
Your sandwiches
will be right out.
- Shrimp here, guys.
- Anything they're not selling?
- No.
If they're not,
then you just remind them.
Hey, push the sandwich.
Hey, push the dip.
You know what I mean, yeah?
- Yeah.
I think we're gonna put a good
variety of everything.
This is good for three?
I feel like this experience
has changed me for the better.
I feel like
it's given me a lot of tools
that I didn't have before,
taught me a lot of things in
the kitchen that I didn't know.
I feel overall like
a more well-rounded chef.
I'm very excited.
Thank you so much.
[soaring orchestral music]
- The sauce is very good.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm very proud of our team.
It's nice that she's actually
here communicating with us,
helping us.
It feels great.
- Customers are saying that the
food is amazing, really good.
I had no complaints tonight.
They said they couldn't
wait to come back.
Something that
we don't hear very often.
- What do you think Gus is
going to think about the food?
- Hi, boss.
- I believe Gus cannot
recognize his own restaurant.
♪ ♪
I think he's proud
of all of us.
- Are you happy?
- Yes, I am.
- You love everything?
- I love it.
- I'm pretty sure
he will be a new Gus.
He'll be a good guy.
- And you are gonna be amazed
at how smooth it runs back here
with that menu being as
small as it is and everything
being as fresh as it is.
I think Gus is going to
fall in love with the
restaurant again,
give him a passion again
for coming to work
and wanting
to run the restaurant
like I know he used to.
- [sighs]
- Right, listen.
Well done.
You have been amazing.
- Thank you.
- OK?
- Understand the strength
and the power you've got
over this diner.
Let's see what Gus does next
to keep this place on track.
Now I said from day one,
the problem wasn't the service.
OK?
We know who the problem was.
I'd like to think
we've started to sort him out.
- Yes.
- We're going forwards,
not backwards.
all: Yes.
- Thank you so much.
Oh, I am very excited
for the future.
It feels good.
Everybody's happy.
I'm happy, they're happy,
the cooks are happy,
so yeah, I really love it.
- Yeah!
- I'm gonna miss you guys.
- And we're going
to miss you, guy.
- Right. Come in here,
come in here, come in here,
come in here.
- I love it.
- Let's go.
- I'm happy that
Gordon came in and helped us.
And honestly, I'm excited
to see where we go from here.
- It's so nice.
- You happy?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Look after yourself, OK?
It's a new, empowered kitchen.
- Yeah.
- And there's a new vibe
inside the 4-Star Diner.
- You're a strong woman, OK?
And you've taken a lot
and you deserve more.
♪ ♪
Take care, yeah?
Thank you.
♪ ♪
[soaring orchestral music]
Honestly, that was unbelievably
challenging, let me tell you.
A wonderful staff.
They were terrified
of their owner,
working each and every day
never knowing what side of Gus
they were going to encounter.
After what I witnessed,
I wasn't sure whether
I should help Gus.
But in the end, he has
the staff that is hardworking,
that are loyal,
and in love with what they do,
and they're embedded
in this very community.
That's the reason I stayed.
Athens wasn't built in a day,
right?
So let's see how Gus
does from here on in.
Fingers crossed.
And toes.
[peaceful music]
- First of all,
I want to thank
Gordon Ramsay and his team
for making this possible.
That remodeling looks great.
Our business picked up
more than 30%.
Customers love it.
Our team is doing great.
And I hope to see you again,
Gordon Ramsay.
- Too much gravy on the lamb.
- She full of [bleep].
I scream, I bitch.
DJ!
[bleep].
Read your [bleep] ticket!
- Are you delusional?
- No. Are you?
[bleep].
Some of the customers are
just [bleep].
- No, no, no!
Wow!
What's she doing?